<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.101.0">Hugo</generator><title>Security on Ukmac.net</title><link href="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Security/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HTML"/><link href="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Security/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Atom"/><updated>2022-08-06T22:22:08+00:00</updated><id>https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Security/</id><entry><title>Hackers find way of breaking out of Apple's sand box ( OS X and iOS )</title><link href="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2015-06-17-hackers-find-way-of-breaking-out-of-apples-sand-box-os-x-and-ios/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2015-06-17-hackers-find-way-of-breaking-out-of-apples-sand-box-os-x-and-ios/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>Just this afternoon I was involved in a discussion about how hackers exploit the most difficult to find holes in operating systems, networks and hardware to gain a way in or in some cases out of the protections wrapped around our technology by the people who developed them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These protections are increasingly complex and sophisticated but as
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://arstechnica.com/security/2015/06/serious-os-x-and-ios-flaws-let-hackers-steal-keychain-1password-contents/"
>this article from Ars Technica&lt;/a> shows the bad guys ( or good guys if they are doing this to expose weaknesses to the vendors rather than using for personal gain ) continue to find ways around and through the barriers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple have long claimed that their operating systems and software are best in class as far as security is concerned, but as we all know these sort of claims are only going to encourage hackers to prove them wrong, more so over recent years as Apples market share has grown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully steps are already in place to fix this latest vulnerability.&lt;/p></content><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Security" term="Security" label="Security"/></entry><entry><title>Near Lock - Unlock your Mac with your iPhone or Apple Watch</title><link href="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-04-06-near-lock-unlock-mac-iphone-apple-watch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-04-06-near-lock-unlock-mac-iphone-apple-watch/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/near-lock-lock-unlock-your/id886882252?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Near Lock&lt;/a> is a new pair of apps for iOS and OS X that allows you to unlock your Mac with your iPhone or Apple Watch. Once installed and configured the app can be configured to lock or unlock your Mac as soon as it detects the presence of your iPhone. The sensitivity of the detection can be adjusted from as little as 1m to as much as 10m so you can optimise the point at which it locks or unlocks your Mac according to your requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The app works with recent iPhones and Macs that support Bluetooth LE and as a result can be left switched on all the time without it causing a significant drain on iPhone batteries. Furthermore the currently free in app upgrade to the Pro version on iOS allows the app to work even when in the background so there is no need to unlock your iPhone or run an app to unlock your Mac. If you are worried that just being able to walk up to your Mac with your iPhone is a little insecure ( think someone gets your phone and can unlock and access your Mac ) then the iOS app can be setup to require Touch ID authentication before it will unlock which is a nice but still convenient way of accessing your Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonderful stuff&amp;hellip; Get it now while it is free !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/near-lock-lock-unlock-your/id886882252?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Web Site :
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://nearlock.me"
>Near Lock&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Apps" term="Apps" label="Apps"/><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/iOS" term="iOS" label="iOS"/><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Security" term="Security" label="Security"/></entry><entry><title>Show Me Yours - A New Campaign Video from Liberty Human Rights Group</title><link href="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-05-06-show-me-yours-a-new-campaign-video-from-liberty-human-rights-group/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-05-06-show-me-yours-a-new-campaign-video-from-liberty-human-rights-group/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>Show Me Yours is a wonderful tongue in cheek video featuring comedian
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivia_Lee"
>Olivia Lee&lt;/a> in which she is seen walking up to strangers in the street asking to see whats on their mobile phones. The video was produced by Liberty a Human Rights Group to highlight to the public the potential far reaching consequences if the so called &amp;ldquo;Snoopers Charter&amp;rdquo; is passed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The video is shown below along with the press release from Liberty that explains in more detail what the group is doing to raise awareness of this critically important issue. Please share this video widely. Thank you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[embed]https://youtu.be/szN7DlmMLYg[/embed]&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h2 id="liberty-launches-film-to-bring-home-true-scale-of-new-snoopers-charter">
LIBERTY LAUNCHES FILM TO BRING HOME TRUE SCALE OF NEW SNOOPERS’ CHARTER
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-05-06-show-me-yours-a-new-campaign-video-from-liberty-human-rights-group/#liberty-launches-film-to-bring-home-true-scale-of-new-snoopers-charter" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor LIBERTY LAUNCHES FILM TO BRING HOME TRUE SCALE OF NEW SNOOPERS’ CHARTER" href="#liberty-launches-film-to-bring-home-true-scale-of-new-snoopers-charter">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Human rights group Liberty has today launched a short film highlighting the unprecedented, unnecessary and deeply intrusive spying powers handed to hundreds of public bodies by the latest incarnation of the Snoopers’ Charter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The video created by Liberty and creative agency Don’t Panic, sees comedian Olivia Lee take to the streets demanding a look at strangers’ most personal and sensitive information – the same information to which a broad range of public bodies will gain unfettered access if the Investigatory Powers Bill becomes law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team who brought you ‘The Revolution Will Be Televised’ got together again to bring you ‘Show me yours&amp;hellip;.’. Joe Wade, MD at Don’t Panic notes: &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“We used hidden cameras to pick up people’s reaction caused by Olivia’s invasive baiting which highlights that people do and should care about their privacy. The use of hidden cameras was to reflect the very nature of how the government plans to pass this bill, hidden from the public and to convey a sense of unwarranted invasiveness that will come with the Snoopers’ Charter.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Liberty is calling on the public to sign up to its No #SnoopersCharter campaign and urge their MPs to reject the Bill when they vote on it this summer. This is one of the most intrusive and least accountable surveillance regimes in the world. There is a consensus from service providers, tech experts and three cross-party parliamentary committees that its plans are unclear, unworkable and potentially unlawful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bill, currently being rushed through Parliament, will force telecoms companies to store everybody’s communications data for an entire year, this includes every site we visit, every communication programme and app we use, every system update we download and details of any device we use to go online (at huge cost to the public purse).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bill would also legalise:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mass hacking of phones and other devices by the intelligence agencies, capable of dangerously undermining Britain’s digital infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bulk interception of calls, emails, online exchanges and texts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Acquiring vast databases containing personal information on millions of people – potentially the whole population.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Powers to force telecoms operators here and abroad, from Gmail, Facebook and Twitter to offices, businesses and law firms, to remove encryption – and ban them from revealing they have been forced to do so.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h3 id="call-to-action">
CALL TO ACTION:
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-05-06-show-me-yours-a-new-campaign-video-from-liberty-human-rights-group/#call-to-action" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor CALL TO ACTION:" href="#call-to-action">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Please watch and share this video to encourage people to join the and help protect our human rights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For campaign page:
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.nosnooperscharter.org.uk"
>http://www.nosnooperscharter.org.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Video link:
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://youtu.be/szN7DlmMLYg"
>https://youtu.be/szN7DlmMLYg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hashtag: #snooperscharter&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h3 id="quotes-from-team">
Quotes from team:
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/posts/2016-05-06-show-me-yours-a-new-campaign-video-from-liberty-human-rights-group/#quotes-from-team" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor Quotes from team:" href="#quotes-from-team">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bella Sankey, Policy Director for Liberty, said: “As this film shows, people in Britain value their personal privacy – even Home Office staff are unwilling to reveal their phone records for no good reason. But the Government’s latest Snoopers’ Charter would make everyone’s online activity available to the authorities to speculatively trawl through without good reason and without us ever being told.It will all but end online privacy, put our personal security at risk and swamp law enforcement with swathes of useless information. People need to make it clear to MPs – we don’t want the Government building profiles of our personal lives with no justification and this Bill must stopped.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Joe Wade, MD, Don’t Panic: “We are delighted to have worked with Liberty to make this video. Many people are complaisant about the surveillance bill, and so we wanted to highlight how invasive it will be! For this video we used a political satire format that has hugely successful for other videos we have created. Our aim was to create something that would tackle this challenging and very relevant subject in an honest way. Our team worked very closely with Liberty throughout the process; from establishing the initial hidden camera concept to developing the tone/messaging, to filming and the final delivery.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Thanks,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jon&lt;/p></content><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Humour" term="Humour" label="Humour"/><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Security" term="Security" label="Security"/><category scheme="https://ukmac.github.io/blog/tags/Videos" term="Videos" label="Videos"/></entry></feed>