<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.101.0">Hugo</generator><title>Hints and Tips on Ukmac.net</title><link href="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HTML"/><link href="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Atom"/><updated>2022-08-06T22:05:39+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips/</id><entry><title>Calls To 0800 Numbers Free From Mobiles Starting 1st July (UK)</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2015-06-19-calls-to-0800-numbers-free-from-mobiles-starting-1st-july-uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2015-06-19-calls-to-0800-numbers-free-from-mobiles-starting-1st-july-uk/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>I just happened across this tidbit and though its not really Mac or Apple related I thought it was worth posting a quick note about it because I expect many people in the UK may not be aware of the forthcoming changes to telephone call charges that come into force on 1st July 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the information you need can be found at
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://ukcalling.info"
>http://ukcalling.info&lt;/a>. There are a range of changes being made to make the charges for 08 numbers clearer to UK residents amongst which is the change that makes 0800 and 0808 calls free to mobiles as well as landlines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good news for many people I would think.&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/></entry><entry><title>Copied - Sync your clipboard for iOS and OS X</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-06-copied-sync-clipboard-ios-os-x/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2016-04-06-copied-sync-clipboard-ios-os-x/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/copied-copy-paste-everywhere/id1015767349?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Copied&lt;/a> has recently become one of my favourite apps for iOS and OS X. It is a slick and useful clipboard manager that makes cut/copy and paste on iPhone,iPad and Mac much more useful and when combined with multiple devices introduces a new capability that was previously only possible by emailing or Messaging between devices. That feature is the ability to copy something on one device then jump over to another and paste that data on another device !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>more&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/copied-copy-paste-everywhere/id1015767349?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>iOS version&lt;/a> has a free to use version that allows you to save up to 10 entries into the clipboard and to recall any of these to paste into another app. The entries can be free text, images and links and importantly can be edited after being captured into the clipboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h2 id="in-use-on-ios">
In Use on iOS
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-06-copied-sync-clipboard-ios-os-x/#in-use-on-ios" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor In Use on iOS" href="#in-use-on-ios">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Pasting an existing entry from the clipboard can be done in a number of ways. Firstly you can load the app and scroll through the list of entries to find the one you want. Once located tap on the entry and it opens in an editor where ( if the entry is text ) you can edit the contents of the clipboard if required. From here you also have a standard iOS Share button which allows you to send the entry to a suitable app as a new item ( document/tweet/Message etc ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively you can click on the three dots icon to either copy the entry into the current clipboard ( so you can paste it into another app/document ), Share using a template or Transform the text if applicable. Transforming text gives options to convert to upper/lower/title case, removing whitespace etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img
src="http://ukmac.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/copiedv2.gif"
alt="copiedv2"
/>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h2 id="copied-keyboard">
Copied Keyboard
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-06-copied-sync-clipboard-ios-os-x/#copied-keyboard" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor Copied Keyboard" href="#copied-keyboard">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The other method for accessing clipboard entries is through the Copied keyboard. This is accessed in the same way as other third party iOS keyboards by tapping the globe key on the standard keyboard to cycle through any additional keyboards you have installed. The keyboard replaces the normal keys with a grid of clipboard entries which you can scroll through ( sideways ) to find the entry you wish to paste into your document or text. Just tap the entry to paste the data at the cursor. Simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h2 id="copied">
Copied+
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-06-copied-sync-clipboard-ios-os-x/#copied" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor Copied&amp;#43;" href="#copied">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>For a small in-app purchase ( £1.49 in UK ) the basic free version can be upgraded to Copied+ which increases the clipboard size to 1,000 items and also includes the ability to organise clippings into Lists for better organisation. For example I have is a list of clippings for my address, mobile phone number etc which I can then use to quickly enter these into web forms.
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/copied-copy-paste-everywhere/id1015767349?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Copied+&lt;/a> also enables iCloud sync of the clipboard between devices as mentioned at the beginning of this review.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gblog-post__anchorwrap">
&lt;h2 id="copied-for-mac">
Copied for Mac
&lt;a data-clipboard-text="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-06-copied-sync-clipboard-ios-os-x/#copied-for-mac" class="gblog-post__anchor clip flex align-center" aria-label="Anchor Copied for Mac" href="#copied-for-mac">
&lt;svg class="gblog-icon gblog_link">&lt;use xlink:href="#gblog_link">&lt;/use>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The synchronisation doesn&amp;rsquo;t end with iOS though, when used in conjunction with the OS X version of the app data can be easily transferred between Mac and iPhone/iPad in just the same way. This is an incredibly useful feature and one that would really fit into the core operating system on these devices if Apple ever saw fit to develop this, however for now
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/copied-copy-paste-everywhere/id1015767349?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Copied&lt;/a> fills this space very nicely. It should be said that the OS X version of the app is £5.99 which isn&amp;rsquo;t free and there are other apps that provide similar features, but in my experience using Copied is a smooth and effective way of improving the way in which I can transfer data between apps on my iPhone and also between iPhone and Mac and I believe the overall benefit is worth the small outlay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/copied-copy-paste-everywhere/id1015767349?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Copied for iOS&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/copied-copy-paste-everywhere/id1026349850?mt=12&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Copied for OS X&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://copiedapp.com"
>Copied Web Site&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Apps" term="Apps" label="Apps"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/iOS" term="iOS" label="iOS"/></entry><entry><title>For You Disappearing from iTunes after recent update</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2015-07-15-for-you-disappearing-from-itunes-after-recent-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2015-07-15-for-you-disappearing-from-itunes-after-recent-update/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>Last night my MacBook&amp;rsquo;s iTunes was updated with the latest release ( 12.2.1.16 ) and when it restarted I was prompted with the invitation to Join Apple Music trial. As I had already signed up I ignored this prompt and clicked through to iTunes assuming it was some sort of error, however what I noticed then was the For You and New sections at the top of the iTunes window were now missing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Restarting iTunes didn&amp;rsquo;t resolve this, nor did logging out of the the Store and back in again. After a number of attempts to recover the missing sections I went into the iTunes Store and clicked onto the 90 Day Trial link ( at the very bottom left of the store ) and hey presto the missing sections re-appeared again !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyone else experienced this or was this a one off for me ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Apple-Music" term="Apple-Music" label="Apple Music"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/></entry><entry><title>Free Markdown Video Tutorial Series</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2016-03-29-free-markdown-video-tutorial-series/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2016-03-29-free-markdown-video-tutorial-series/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"
>Markdown&lt;/a> is the plain text markup syntax developed by
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://twitter.com/daringfireball"
>John Gruber&lt;/a> of
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://daringfireball.net"
>Daring Fireball&lt;/a> over 10 years ago to help bloggers write in a readable format that could be easily converted to HTML. Since then it has grown in popularity and spawned a whole ecosystem of applications and tools for the easy management and production of Markdown formatted documents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The syntax is simple to learn but if you want a nice concise set of quick video tutorials then
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://twitter.com/wesbos"
>Wes Bos&lt;/a> has put together a
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://masteringmarkdown.com"
>set of 11 short&lt;/a> ( between 1 and 6 mins long ) guides that take you quickly through the basics of Markdown to get you up and running with minimal effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>link :
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://masteringmarkdown.com"
>Mastering Markdown&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/></entry><entry><title>How do you backup your digital data ?</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2015-07-26-how-do-you-backup-your-digital-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2015-07-26-how-do-you-backup-your-digital-data/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>Unless you have a background in IT the chances are that the only time you have ever considered backups of your information was just after you found out you had lost something precious ? Perhaps it was a bunch of irretrievable photos lost when your hard drive suddenly and inexplicably died ? Or maybe it was your lifetimes collection of music or movies, carefully downloaded and collated onto that 4TB external hard drive connected to your desktop computer that you hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed had been accidentally deleted ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whichever it was, when the day arrives and you suffer that unrecoverable data loss the chances are you will be asking yourself why you hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to backup to another disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My preferred and recommended backup solution is an online service called
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://backblaze.com"
>Backblaze&lt;/a>. Backblaze is cheap ( as little as $5 a month ), reliable and easy to setup and better yet, once configured you can forget it is there and relax in the knowledge that should the worst happen your data is safe and easily retrieved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link--raw"
href="https://secure.backblaze.com/r/00isdf"
>&lt;img
src="http://ukmac.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/backblaze-trial-300x250.gif"
alt="backblaze trial"
/>&lt;/a>Unlike most Internet file storage solutions (
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="www.dropbox.com"
>Dropbox&lt;/a>,
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="onedrive.com"
>OneDrive&lt;/a> etc ) the cost for Backblaze is the same whether you are backing up 100MB or 20TB ! The only difference will be the amount of time it takes to complete the initial backup, something that is getting easier as home broadband speeds steadily increase. This initial &amp;ldquo;seeding&amp;rdquo; of your backup may take some weeks to complete but it happens in the background and is carefully controlled by the
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="www.backblaze.com"
>Backblaze&lt;/a> software to not interfere with your Internet access too much. Once the first backup is complete the software then only has to update the backup when anything changes to your local data, again a process that happens in the background without manual intervention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Backblaze will backup any of your hard drives, not just the internal drive in your PC or Mac. Just plugin your external USB drives, configure the application settings and wait for the data to be secured. One thing to note here though is that if you do this Backblaze needs to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; that drive at least once every 30 days or it will assume the data does not need to be retained and will delete it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously paying for backup services is not sexy, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give you anything other than piece of mind, but it is something that everyone who has any amount of data in digital form should consider putting in place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you would like to try out Backblaze you can sign up for a
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://secure.backblaze.com/r/00isdf"
>months free trial by clicking on this link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is not sponsored by Backblaze it is purely my personal choice of backup service and something that I recommend to friends and relatives when the subject arises. Please try it out, you may thank me one day !&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Apps" term="Apps" label="Apps"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/></entry><entry><title>How to Access Magazines on Zinio for Free</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2015-06-24-how-to-access-magazines-on-zinio-for-free/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2015-06-24-how-to-access-magazines-on-zinio-for-free/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>In the days before the Internet I was a regular magazine subscriber and the shelves in my home office used to groan under the weight of all those glossy pages. My magazine buying days have long since gone, replaced by a diet of online news delivered first by USENET followed by online forums, web sites and most recently RSS feeds read through services like
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://feedly.com"
>Feedly.com&lt;/a> or apps like
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://flipboard.com"
>Flipboard&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Earlier this year I started a volunteer role at my local library to show local residents how to use the library computers or if they prefer their own devices to get more out of the Internet and PC and tablet applications. It was during my familiarisation with the library services on their web site that I came across
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.telford.gov.uk/info/1012/libraries/668/emagazines"
>this page&lt;/a> ! Basically library members can register for FREE to access a range of magazines through the popular service 
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://zinio.com"
>Zinio.com&lt;/a>. Zinio has been around for a long time and I had looked at the magazines available through the service over the years, in fact before I spotted the library link I had been debating subscribing to National Geographic for cash ! So glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t now as the Nat Geo is one of the magazines available through the Telford library service for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that is needed to take advantage of the deal is a library membership card ( available for free to local residents ). Once you are a member you can register through the link on the library web site which gives you access to select from the range of magazines that the library make available ( currently 31 titles at Telford ) and download to your tablet/desktop Zinio reader app or to read online through the Zinio web site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since signing up for this service I have spoken with a variety of friends and work colleagues and told them how I can access magazines online for free. When we have looked at the services available from their local libraries ( Birmingham, Wolverhampton, Walsall etc ) we have discovered that they also offer the same sort of service. In fact most of them have a wider range of magazine titles available than my library in Telford !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you would like to subscribe to this service head over to your local library web site and do a search for Zinio, I am betting that you will find there is a free service available to you that you didn&amp;rsquo;t know was there !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy,&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Apps" term="Apps" label="Apps"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/></entry><entry><title>On How I Lost Then Found Trackpad Options in El Capitan</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-23-on-how-i-lost-then-found-trackpad-options-in-el-capitan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2016-04-23-on-how-i-lost-then-found-trackpad-options-in-el-capitan/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>My normal approach when a new version of OS X is released is to backup ( create a
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://bombich.com"
>Carbon Copy Cloner&lt;/a> image of my main drive ) and then do a clean install ( erase the entire drive and install from scratch ). Obviously this takes a little more time and effort than a normal upgrade but I tend to prefer knowing that any legacy cruft built up over the life of the previous version is washed away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.apple.com/uk/osx/?cid=wwa-uk-kwg-mac"
>El Capitan&lt;/a> was released last year I decided not to bother with a clean install on my MacBook and ran an upgrade and everything has worked fine since then until the last week or so. Firstly disk space has been getting low on my 256GB drive which is never great but then I started to experience a problem with the App Store taking a long time to load which deteriorated to the point where no matter how long I left it running the content in the main panes failed to materialise at all. As I wanted to load a particular new app this was a bit of a problem to say the least. I looked for solutions to the issue without much success ( admittedly I didn&amp;rsquo;t look that hard ) before deciding to do a re-install to freshen up my OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roll forward a couple of hours and I have a clean install of
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.apple.com/uk/osx/?cid=wwa-uk-kwg-mac"
>El Capitan&lt;/a>, my essential data restored from backup, apps reinstalled and App Store fully working. I also now have 140GB of my 256GB drive still free which shows how much disk space can get swallowed up by working files and general detritus in the course of a year. Granted there are a few things I have chosen not to restore but nothing that would account for 100GB of disk space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, all this brings me to the point of this article which is how to enable three finger drag of windows in
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.apple.com/uk/osx/?cid=wwa-uk-kwg-mac"
>El Capitan&lt;/a> ! When the re-install had finished one of the first things I did was to go to System Preferences to sort out my Trackpad settings. By default my three main tweaks to the standard configuration are to switch off natural scrolling ( I know old habits die hard ), switch on tap to click and finally switch on the option to drag windows with three finger gesture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around the first two options were setup as normal but when I looked for the three finger drag option it seemed to have been moved. I was sure it used to be on the Scroll and Zoom section of the preference pane, or was it under More Gestures ? Nope, not there&amp;hellip; I must admit I looked for an embarrassingly long time going from one tab to the next in the vain hope that somehow I would see it where I hadn&amp;rsquo;t before, but it was gone&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully it only took a minutes Googling to uncover the answer to the missing setting, Apple in their infinite wisdom have decided in
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.apple.com/uk/osx/?cid=wwa-uk-kwg-mac"
>El Capitan&lt;/a> that this is not a Trackpad setting now but an Accessibility option ! To find the setting now first go to Accessibility in System Preferences, click on  
&lt;strong>Trackpad Options&lt;/strong>
and on the popup window tick to
&lt;strong>Enable dragging&lt;/strong>
 and select
&lt;strong>three finger drag&lt;/strong>
from the drop down menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course the other thing I
&lt;strong>should have done&lt;/strong>
was to just type &amp;ldquo;three finger drag&amp;rdquo; into the search field in System Preferences which would have instantly told me I was looking in the wrong place !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;479,480,481&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Mac-Hardware" term="Mac-Hardware" label="Mac Hardware"/></entry><entry><title>Swapping Between Hardware and On Screen Keyboards on iOS</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2016-04-03-swapping-between-hardware-and-on-screen-keyboards-on-ios/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2016-04-03-swapping-between-hardware-and-on-screen-keyboards-on-ios/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>I recently bought the excellent
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B013SL1YXO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=6738&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B013SL1YXO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=muxtoncom-21"
>Logitech K380 Multi-Device Bluetooth Keyboard&lt;/a>&lt;img
src="http://ir-uk.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=muxtoncom-21&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=2&amp;amp;a=B013SL1YXO"
alt=""
/> to share between my iPad, Work laptop and iPhone. It&amp;rsquo;s a great little keyboard, light enough to carry around with a decent layout and spacing that suits my typing style well ( your mileage may vary ). There are however times that I need to switch to the on screen iOS keyboard, typing emojis for example, and I recently discovered this quick tip to bring up the iOS keyboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is double tap on a text field and the on screen keyboard will pop smoothly into view. Once you have completed using it just hit any key on your Bluetooth keyboard and the hardware device will take control again and the on screen keyboard will slide out of the way.&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/iOS" term="iOS" label="iOS"/></entry><entry><title>Using Duet Display As A Primary Monitor</title><link href="http://localhost/posts/2016-01-03-using-duet-display-as-a-primary-monitor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><id>http://localhost/posts/2016-01-03-using-duet-display-as-a-primary-monitor/</id><published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><content type="html">
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/duet-display/id935754064?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Duet Display&lt;/a> is a slick app developed by ex-Apple employees designed to allow your iPad to function as a second monitor on your laptop or iMac using a lightning or iPad 30 pin cable ( for older iPads ). The application works extremely well with none of the lag or latency in display refresh experienced by some of the alternative apps that use the iPads WiFi connection to transfer screen updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the Duet name suggests the intended use for the app is to create an easy to use portable secondary display for MacBook users ( or in fact Windows laptop users as there is a Windows version of the server application as well as one for OS X ) but it isn&amp;rsquo;t limited to this use case. My main use of Duet is as a primary monitor on my Mac Mini media server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have used my Mac Mini in a headless ( no monitor ) setup for a long time and use Screen Sharing from my MacBook to login and manage it, however it recently struck me that the
&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/duet-display/id935754064?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg"
>Duet Display app&lt;/a>that I had purchased some time ago would be perfect for creating a tiny compact keyboard/monitor setup. Combined with a small bluetooth keyboard from Anker and bluetooth mouse I now have full access to my Mini in a compact little setup that looks pretty slick on the shelf in my study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duet Display is £7.99 in the UK iOS App store which I admit is probably at the high side of many peoples acceptable budget for an app of this type, however this app is extremely good and provides amazing functionally and performance. For people who travel with a MacBook and iPad the benefit of being able to setup a usable dual monitor setup whilst on the move can be liberating, and for home media servers like mine it can create a slick, compact and usable alternative to a bulky VGA/HDMI monitor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a
class="gblog-markdown__link"
href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/duet-display/id935754064?mt=8"
>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_228&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;640&amp;rdquo;]
&lt;img
src="http://ukmac.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/IMG_1173.jpg"
alt="Duet Display"
/> Duet Display on iPad and Mac Mini[/caption]&lt;/p></content><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Apps" term="Apps" label="Apps"/><category scheme="http://localhost/tags/Hints-and-tips" term="Hints-and-tips" label="Hints and tips"/></entry></feed>